The number one food to remove fat from
your liver. In the past, a fatty liver
was mostly caused by alcohol. But
nowadays, it's caused by something
different. [music] We're talking about a
problem that can extend beyond the
liver. Issues would be like type 2
[music] diabetes, obesity, high blood
pressure. And this leads me to the
biggest confusion of this disorder. The
medical profession is very careful not
to give you the cause effect
relationship. Instead, they talk about
the risk factors. They list all these
things like obesity and diabetes and
high blood pressure. And if you have
these, you're at risk for getting this
fatty liver issue. This is why they're
even changing the name from non
alcoholic fatty liver disease to
something called MASH, metabolic
dysfunction associated Seattle
hepatitis. Now, what does that mean?
That's basically a fatty liver with
inflammation. They really kind of keep
things disconnected. I mean, it's
obvious to me what's causing it, but for
the average person, it's all kind of
general, kind of confusing. So
basically, they're going to focus in on
the smoke detector without really
looking at the fire behind it. And that
way, we can treat each individual risk
factor with a different medication. Now,
I want to show you a clip of another way
that they hide the real cause. Check
this out. Most of the population has had
excess nutrition day after day after
day. And that's what ends up causing
damage to the liver and many other
organs.
>> I mean, that just sounds funny as a as a
cause for a fatty liver. You're
chronically eating too much nutrition. I
mean, if I just told you right now, you
know, you know, you're suffering from
chronic overnutrition, you might kind of
ask me, "What the heck are you talking
about?" Over nutrition is too much
sugar, too much starch or refined
carbohydrates, or too many seed oils.
They're not nutritious because they
don't have any nutrients. You cannot
live on those foods forever without
getting sick. I'm talking about the
breads, pasta, cereal, crackers,
biscuits, waffles, pancakes, especially
the industrial sugars like the high
fructose corn syrup really hammers the
liver hardcore. Anytime you eat glucose,
all of your cells can metabolize it, but
not fructose. If we look up this disease
online, it'll tell you that rarely are
you going to really experience any
symptom other than fatigue, sometimes
right upper quadrant discomfort, which
by the way, I had for over a decade.
cognitive problems. You're going to
notice like your skin is a bit yellow,
your feet getting hot or itchy. You're
definitely going to notice a gut. You
have just too much fat in your liver
that's spilling off into and around your
organs. If you read a little bit lower
on the page when it talks about the
fatty liver, there's something really
interesting. In the section of diet, it
will talk about what potentially causes
a fatty liver. And they mention red
meat, organ meats, liver, and eggs
causing a fatty liver. If you look up
those studies, they are all
observational studies. So, in other
words, they give you a food
questionnaire and they say, "Remember
what you ate in the last year?" And they
don't pay attention to these other
variables like if you're eating red meat
or eggs, did you eat French fries with
that? Are you eating sugar with that?
Are you smoking? Are you drinking
alcohol with that? They're not really
looking at these other factors. So,
these observational studies are
worthless, and you don't want to use
those. It's the worst type of science.
And when you want to manipulate things
and have the media uh put out certain
things, you're going to use these
observational studies. I mean, if red
meat, liver, and eggs cause this fatty
liver epidemic, then why did this
explosion, this epidemic of a fatty
liver occur after we reduced saturated
fat? Could it possibly be because we
dramatically increased our refined
carbohydrates? There is data to show
that if you go on a lowcarb ketogenic
diet, you can reduce 50% of the fat off
your liver within a few weeks. The
question is, what should you eat? The
last one is going to be the most
powerful. Number one, grass-fed red
meat. It's not necessarily just beef. It
could be lamb as well. What's so special
about that? It helps to restore your
insulin problems and your blood sugar.
It has high quality protein. It has
zinc. It has copper, co-enzyme Q10. All
of these nutrients are super healing for
the liver. Number two, eggs. Because out
of all the nutrients that help protect
you against the fatty liver, that
nutrient is choline. And guess what? Egg
yolks are very high in choline. Egg
yolks are zero carbohydrate. Anything
that is zero carb is going to help
reverse a fatty liver. Number three,
cruciferous vegetables, especially if
it's fermented in the form of
sauerkraut. That will help support the
liver going through its detoxification.
The fermentation part of the cabbage
really will help in removing the fat
from the liver. The other cruciferous
vegetable that I consume a lot of is
arugula. It's slightly bitter. I put my
extra-virgin olive oil on there. And I
also sprinkle some nutritional yeast on
there. Makes a great salad. Plus, when
your microbiome eats some of this fiber,
it gives you all sorts of additional
cool things that will help your blood
sugar as well. Next food on the list is
wild caught salmon or other wild caught
fatty fish that have not only a lot of
nutrition and protein, but they're very
high in omega-3 fatty acids. And what
these omega-3 fatty acids do to the
liver is help reduce inflammation.
Omega-3 fatty acid is really beneficial
to help the liver in many different
ways. And cod liver and cod liver oil.
You talk about taking your omega-3s to
the next level, you just get a lot more.
Next one is broccoli sprouts. What's so
special about broccoli sprouts? Well,
you're dealing with a cruciferous
vegetable which has sulforophane, which
does a lot. It's anti-cancer, but it's
very good to detoxify the liver and
decrease A1C, which will help your blood
sugar. I would take the broccoli sprouts
and put them on your arugula salad.
Let's get to the best food that you can
eat for your liver. And this is going to
be very surprising because it's the
exact thing that they tell you not to
eat for a fatty liver. grass-fed liver,
beef liver or lamb liver has the most
choline. We get this low carb, high
choline, high nutrientdense with most of
the trace minerals like zinc, selenium,
these are all really important in
reducing fat and inflammation off the
liver. Now, of course, if we cook that
liver with the onions, garlic, with our
arugula salad, with broccoli sprouts,
maybe with a little sauerkraut, with egg
on top of that, now you have the best
meal for your liver. Thanks so much for
watching and I will see you in the next
video. Hey, before you leave, I just
wanted to give you a little quick
history on some of the books that I
wrote. This was one of the first books
called Dr. Burke Body Shapes. It was my
attempt at um writing about body types.
Uh what was very interesting about this
book is I actually did all the images
myself. Uh don't ask me why. Um they
look actually not quite as professional
as some of the uh images that I have in
the new book. But anyway, this is my
first attempt right here called Dr.
Burke's Body Shaped Diets. Uh, and then
I wrote a book um, more extensive called
The Seven Principles of Fat Burning. I
don't even have a copy anymore actually
um because it's outdated. Uh, the next
book uh, I put about a thousand hours
into this one right here called The New
Body Type Guide. Major updates on the
body types. Uh, I put a lot of energy
into this. Uh, it has professional
images, graphics, all sorts of things.
Now, the problem with this book is it
doesn't really describe what this is
really about. Body types are only a
small portion of what's in this book.
And that's why I changed the name to the
healthy keto plan. Okay? If you happen
to have this book, you don't really need
this book because there's only very,
very minor updates. But if you don't
have this, you need to get this one
right here. Um, this book goes into
every single detail that you would ever
want to know about. It goes into the
seven principles of fat burning. Goes
into hormones, uh, the body types, the
basic keto plan. It goes into
intermittent fasting. I talk about the
10 fat burning triggers and blockers and
fat burning strategies with a lot of
details in every single chapter. I go
into body issues that interfere with
losing weight. Um there's very few
people that just have a weight problem.
They have a lot of body issues, whether
it's sleeping problems, uh stress
problems, inflammation,
menopause. I cover that extensively in
this book. Then I talk about how to get
rid of stress and I show you a
technique. Uh then I get into exercising
and then I have a lot of really good
recipes in this book as well. So, uh
this is a good reference guide. Um on my
website, if you get this book, you get
this one free. It's called Healthy Keto
and Intermittent Fasting. This is the
shortcut uh quick guide to this book.
And uh the reason I created this book is
to have you within 45 minutes learn how
to do keto, okay, in intermittent
fasting, exactly what you need to do.
Then you can fill in the blanks with
this book right here. So, right now I'm
doing a special. If you get this book,
you get this one totally free. Or you
can go to Amazon and get these
individually. So, I just want to clarify
the difference between this book and
this updated one right here. If you
don't have this, you need to get this
right here. That way, you can get the
exact correct information to do it
healthily.